<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Écu de Marc</title>
    <link>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Écu de Marc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 12:47:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>House Prices and Interest Rates</title>
      <link>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/house-prices-interest-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 12:47:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/house-prices-interest-rates/</guid>
      <description>What is the relationship between house prices and interest rates?
In this post, we try to explain this relationship.
Let us start with one simple example.
Example 1 Let us assume we own a property which, if rented out, can achieve an annual rental income of 12,000.
Furthermore, let us assume that the prevailing interest rate at the time on debt is 8% per annum.
To fund the purchase of said property, we need equity on top of debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Network</title>
      <link>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/money-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 10:18:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/money-network/</guid>
      <description>Money is best thought as a network of credit/debit relationships.
A relatively simple money network is shown in the image below.
   In the image, we can see four actors (A,B,C,D).
Each actor has at least one relationship, denoted by an arrow, with another actor.
For example, taking the arrow going from actor A to actor B, we can see that B owes 100 to A. Looking at the arrow from D to A we can see that D has a credit claim of 10 on A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Money?</title>
      <link>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/what-is-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 13:50:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecudemarc.github.io/posts/what-is-money/</guid>
      <description>What is money?
Is it a medium of exchange?
Is it a convenient tool we all decide to use to carry out transactions?
I would argue it is not a medium of exchange and it is not a convenient tool we use to perform transactions.
Instead, I believe that money is a measurement device of value. In other words, it is a unit of account. Like we use the Fahrenheit scale to measure temperature, we use money to measure value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
